ANTONIO W. FERREIRA

Software Developer

CONTACT

- AntonioWFerreira@beamjobs.com 📨
 - +1 559-316-8123
 - Fresno, CA 93706 Q
 - LinkedIn in
 - Github (

EDUCATION

Bachelor of information
Computer Science
Aston University
April 2012 - September 2016
Aston St, Birmingham B4 7ET, UK

SKILLS

JavaScript (ES6, React, Redux, Node.js) SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL) Cloud (GCP, AWS) Python Typescript HTML/ CSS CI/CD

SUMMARY

A seasoned software engineer who loves building web application. With 5 years of professional work experience, I am a strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Computer Programming focused on Computer Science from the Aston University.

I am specialized in building React web fronted applications using Redux/Redux-Saga for state management and React-hooks for building functional components.

I am familiar with GraphQL api integration using Apollo/Relay and I also using Restful Apis for my web application.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer

Wasobe Inc

September 2021 - July 2022 / Vancouver, BC

- Consulted CTO to deliver latest tech stacks and best industry practices.
- Modified React frontend infrastructure to improve performance & resolve potential issues.
- Improved web application rendering performance 10% faster.

Senior Web Developer

Textual

November 2019 - June 2021 / New York, NY

- Modernized the innovative e-commerce platform by leading the frontend development team as a principle developer.
- Committed to SaaS platform development and maintenance project as a web developer.
- Delivered 100% functional SaaS platform to serveral companies and successfully signed contracts.

Senior Web Developer

SESH, inc

May 2018 - April 2019 / Sydney

Managed a team of 5 web developers to deliver web frontend/backend.
 Organized and launched the entire development process, supervised day -to-day progress of development works of team members.

- Built React web frontend & Node backend, hosted on AWS cloud.
 Developed live streaming & recording platform using wowza, customized
 Jitsl frontend, created WebRTC server in Node.
- Delivered platform to the client successfully in agreed timeline and acquired 100% client satisfaction.